The future isn't big enough for the both of them.
Demolition Man is a crime, action, science fiction
film directed by Marco Brambilla.
In 1996, brash L.A.
detective John Spartan and maniac killer Simon Phoenix are both sentenced to decades
in a cryogenic prison as punishment for a rescue mission gone wrong.
When Phoenix escapes 36 years later to wreak havoc on the future, Spartan
is awakened to capture his nemesis the old-fashioned way.
John Spartan, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Simon Phoenix, played by Wesley Snipes.
Lt. Lenina Huxley, played by Sandra Bullock.
Dr. Raymond Cocteau, played by Nigel Hawthorne.
Alfredo Garcia, played by Benjamin Bratt.
Erwin, played by Rob Schneider.
Demolition Man is a 1993 American science fiction action film
directed by Marco Brambilla in his directorial debut.
It stars Sylvester Stallone, Wesley Snipes, Sandra Bullock, and Nigel Hawthorne.
Stallone plays John Spartan, a risk-taking police officer with a
reputation for causing destruction while carrying out his work.
After a failed attempt to rescue hostages from evil crime lord Simon Phoenix
(Snipes), they are both sentenced to be cryogenically frozen in 1996.
In 2032, Phoenix escapes and the authorities awaken Spartan to help capture him.
The story makes allusions to many other works, including Aldous
Huxley's 1932 dystopian novel Brave New World and H.
Wells's The Sleeper Awakes.
The film was released in the United States on October
8, 1993, to mixed reviews from critics.
It earned $159 million worldwide, and was
considered a successful film for Stallone.
The film explores themes of future, martial arts,
helicopter, police, psychopath.
The tone is thought_provoking.